

Nikita Lindemann Data Scientist



Russian Federation, Moscow





lindemann.nikita@gmail.com

nikita-lindemann

NikLinMIPT

Skills -

Computer Vision

Deep Learning

Machine Learning

Python

PyTorch

TensorFlow

OpenCV

Git

Linux

SQL

C++

Russian

Profile

4 years of experience with machine learning models, data preparation and training neural networks using TensorFlow and PyTorch frameworks. The use of various architectures of convolutional neural networks for solving CV problems, integration of the developed modules.

Experience in back-end development in Python: developing client-server applications (asyncio, threads, multiprocessing, flask), working with Shared Memory and Pipe, Development modules for working with devices (lidars, uninterruptible power supply). MLOps experience: deploying, configuring and monitoring modules using python, systemctl, ansible, docker, SQL.

Education

2018 - 2023 Bachelor of Mathematics and Physics Moscow Institute of Physics and Technology Department of Control and Applied Mathematics

Courses

2019-2020 Neural Networks, Mail.ru

2019-2022 Machine learning and math teacher at HSE, Sber, MIPT

Experience

2019-2020 Junior Data scientist. MIPT Cognitive Dynamic Systems Lab

- 1. Collected and labeled data for computer vision tasks.
- 2. Developed computer vision systems for self-driving vehicles using convolutional neural networks.
- 3. Solved the problem of classifying road scene objects (traffic lights and road signs).
- 4. Developed classification module and successfully implemented in the competition of self-driving vehicles "Winter City".

2021-2023 ML CV Engineer, Deputy Head of Department. Glosav

- 1. Developed video analytics systems.
- 2. Solved problems of classification, detection and tracking using CNN.
- 3. Developed infrastructure for integrating video analytics systems.
- 4. Optimization and integration of convolutional neural networks on mini PCs (jetson, firefly) using ONNX, TensorRT, RKNN.
- Developed, supported and integrated the following modules: license plate recognition, vehicle detection and classification, face detection and classification, vehicle tracking, lidar data capture, vehicle dimensions calculation.
- Developed and successfully implemented a face recognition and people counting system for VDNKH (Moscow subway station) with a load more than 2000 people per hour.
- 7. Developed and successfully implemented an intelligent system for collecting tolls on the federal highways M1 and M4 with a load more than 5000 vehicles daily.
- 8. Compilation of technical specifications and setting tasks for developers and engineers, analysis of the necessary equipment (mini PCs, cameras, sensors, etc.) and preparation of technical specifications for purchasing department, communication with customers. Participation in the process of hiring and training new employees.